Guide to the New York University Archives Collection of Late 19th Century Photographic Materials MC.230
New York University Archives
New York University Archives Collection of Late 19th Century Photographic Materials
1862-1926
1862-1898
New York University Archives
Draper, Henry, 1837-1882
Hering, D.W. (Daniel Webster), 1850-1938
Dixon, Antonia
MC.230
13 Linear Feet in 34 custom boxes, 3 oversize flat boxes, 1 small flat box, and 2 card boxes.
The New York University Archives Collection of Late 19th Century Photographic Materials is an artificial collection containing images captured on a variety of obsolete photographic formats including lantern slides, glass plate negatives, and daguerreotypes. This collection includes astrophotographic images by NYU professor and dean, Henry Draper; x-ray images by NYU professor D.W. Hering; University Heights campus and student images; and lantern slides of images used for presentations and lectures.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Upon Henry Draper's death in 1882 a selection of items in this collection were found in his New York laboratory. Draper's sister, Mrs. Antonia Dixon, presented these items to New York University. The accession number related to this collection is 82.030.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged into ten series, arranged in chronological order within.
Series I. Henry Draper Spectra Images
Series II. Henry Draper Moon Images
Series III. Glass Plate Negative Fragments
Series IV. Henry Draper-Related Observatories and Laboratories Images
Series V. D.W. Hering X-Ray Images
Series VI. NYU Campus, Students, and Related Images
Series VII. Lecture Presentation Support Images
Series VIII. Daguerreotypes
Series IX. Document Reproductions and Memorial Images
Series X. Original Storage Housing
Historical Note
This collection was created by University Archives staff to provide access to obsolete photographic formats which had been donated from various sources.
Biographical Note
Henry Draper (1837-1882) was an American doctor who became a professor and dean of the medical faculty at the University of the City of New York (now New York University) from 1866 until his death in 1882. He was also well known for his work in astrophotography.
Biographical Note
D.W. (Daniel Webster) Hering (1850-1938) was appointed professor of physics at NYU in 1885. He was known for his early work in Roentgen X-rays and took what may be considered the first radiograph of an entire human body. Hering became Dean of the Graduate School of Arts and Science in 1902 and served in that post until his retirement in 1916.
Custodial History
This is an assembled collection comprised of materials from multiple sources and creators. The initial donation in 1882 included Henry Draper images which were taken from his New York City area laboratory. Additional material was later added to the collection including photographic and radiographic items which had been taken by D.W. Hering. These items had been found in NYU Heights campus building attic.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Due to the fragile nature of the original materials, researchers must use the digital surrogates which are available through this finding aid.
Related Materials
Draper Family Papers (MC 11)
Henry Draper Collection of Scientific Instruments (MC 291)
D.W. Hering Papers (MC 74)
Symposium on the Orion Nebula to Honor Henry Draper Symposium on the Orion Nebula to Honor Henry Draper (1981: New York University)
Scope and Contents
The New York University Archives Collection of Late 19th Century Photographic Materials is an artificial collection containing images captured on a variety of obsolete photographic formats including lantern slides, glass plate negatives, and daguerreotypes.
This collection includes images taken by NYU professor and dean Henry Draper during the 1860s through the early 1880s related to his study of astrophotography. Images were often taken of the night sky at an observatory through his telescope, and document spectra, solar spectrum, and the moon. There are also images of Draper's observatory and lab at Hastings-on-Hudson as well as the observatories at Harvard College which were funded in his memory by Draper's widow Anna Palmer Draper in 1886. Some of these glass plate negative slides have been damaged and now only exist in partial fragments. Wooden containers which originally housed Draper's glass plate negatives are this collection.
The majority of the lantern slides in this collection were used as illustrations in presentations and lectures. These slides include a significant number of reproductions of Draper's astrophotographic work including the moon dating from the 1860s, solar spectra, early solar spectrum, and the sun. The lantern slides containing radiographic images of everyday objects taken by D.W. Hering and C.L. Bristol, related to their work in x-rays. Presentation and lecture images also include stock footage of landscapes, cityscapes, Johnstown ruins, and artworks.
Images from the late 1890s of NYU's University Heights campus, including buildings and students, as well as photographs used in a 1914 NYU publication about student life, are also in this collection.
Biographical Note
Charles Lawrence (C.L.) Bristol (1859-1931) was a professor of biology at New York University from 1894 to 1931. Bristol began teaching in the biology department at NYU's University Heights campus in 1894. He taught an array of courses such as human anatomy and physiology, general biology, comparative anatomy, and vertebrate zoology.
Daguerreotype; Lantern slides; Glass plate negatives; Photographic prints.; Astronomical photography; Astronomy.; Dixon, Antonia; New York University -- Faculty -- 19th century; Bristol, Charles Lawrence, 1859-1931
- Series I. Henry Draper Spectra Images, 1873-1882; 2 Linear Feet in 8 small half manuscript boxes, 1 oversize flat box, and 5 custom boxes.
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains images dating from 1873 to 1882 taken by New York University professor, dean of medicine, and amateur astrophotographer, Henry Draper. This images in this series are related to Draper's pursuit of astrophotography and his related experiments. Subjects include spectra and solar spectra contrasted with various gases and elements.
  - Spectra, August 11, 1870s; cuid1912 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Spectra, August 12, 1873; cuid1911 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Spectra -- No. 2, 12 January 1876; cuid1924 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Cyanogen, 23 April 1876; cuid1960 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Spectra, 19 June 1876; cuid1919 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Print of Solar Spectrum -- Discovery of Oxygen in the Sun, 1876; cuid2027 (Box 34, Folder 2)
    Upper part of photograph is spectrum of sun. Lower part is spectrum of oxygen and nitrogen of air. This is the illustration (probably the original for the reproduction) in the paper about oxygen in the sun (J. Franklin Institute vol. 74).
  - Sun and Air (Leyden Spark) with Coincidence of Oxygen Lines with Bright Lines in the Sun, 1876; cuid2044 (Box 37, Folder 7)
  - Spectrum of CO2 -- Voighander Between Slit of Plage-Browning Prism Close to Slit, February 1877; cuid1954 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Hydrogen 800 Ten Sparks Per Minute --- Browning of Prisms, 14 February 1877; cuid1962 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Hydrogen -- 800 Ten Inch Sparks Per Minute -- 10m Ex. -- Browning of Prism, 14 February 1877; cuid1970 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Sun 5S Nitrogen 800 Ten Inch Sparks Per Minute, 17 February 1877; cuid1964 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Solar Spectrum with Comparison, 18 February 1877; cuid2074 (Box 39)
  - Hydrogen 15m Ex. 800 Sparks Per Minute -- No Leyden -- No. 2, 1 March 1877; cuid1967 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Hydrogen -- No Leyden -- 15m Ex...No.3, 1 March 1877; cuid1968 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Hydrogen -- No Leyden, 3 March 1877; cuid1966 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Hydrogen 2nd Ex. of Tube 10m-800 Sparks Red -- No. Leyden, 18 March 1877; cuid1958 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Solar Spectrum with Comparison Identification, 24 March 1877; cuid2073 (Box 39)
  - Leyden, 24 March 1877; cuid1956 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Solar Spectrum with Nitrogen Lab Spectrum for Comparison, 1 April 1877; cuid2067 (Box 39)
  - Solar Spectrum with CO2, 3 April 1877; cuid2076 (Box 39)
  - Solar Spectrum with Air for Comparison, 7 April 1877; cuid2071 (Box 39)
  - Solar Spectrum with Nitrogen Laboratory Spectrum, 11 April 1877; cuid2064 (Box 39)
  - Solar Spectrum with Comparison CO2 Identifications, 15 April 1877; cuid2070 (Box 39)
  - Solar Spectrum with Comparison Spectrum, 15 April 1877; cuid2061 (Box 38, Folder 13)
  - Laboratory Spectrum, 17 April 1877; cuid2063 (Box 38, Folder 15)
  - Cyanogen Laboratoy Spectrum, 17 April 1877; cuid2072 (Box 39)
  - Chloride of Tin -- Nitrogen Only, 18 April 1877; cuid1948 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Bromide of Silicon, 18 April 1877; cuid1957 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Fluoride of Silicon Laboratory Spectrum, 23 April 1877; cuid2054 (Box 38, Folder 6)
  - Bromide of Silicon Laboratory Spectrum, 23 April 1877; cuid2079 (Box 39)
  - Cyanogen, 23 April 1877; cuid1955 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Carbonic Acid, 28 April 1877; cuid1961 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Carbonic Acid Laboratory Spectrum, 1 May 1877; cuid2066 (Box 39)
  - Carbonic Acid Laboratory Spectrum, 3 May 1877; cuid2060 (Box 38, Folder 12)
  - Spectrum of Sulphuret of L--, 21 May 1877; cuid1971 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Solar Spectrum with Comparison, 29 May 1877; cuid2078 (Box 39)
  - Iodine, December 1877; cuid1900 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Spectrum of Iodine, December 1877; cuid1905 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Spectrum, 1877; cuid2062 (Box 38, Folder 14)
  - Sulphur, 1 January 1878; cuid1953 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Sulphur, 1 January 1878; cuid1973 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Spectra, 5 January 1878; cuid1893 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Spectra, 6 January 1878; cuid1888 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Sulphuretted Hydrogen, 14 February 1878; cuid1952 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Coal Gas Laboratory Spectrum, 14 February 1878; cuid2057 (Box 38, Folder 9)
  - Spectra, 15 March 1878; cuid1932 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Spectra, 16 March 1878; cuid1949 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Solar Spectrum with Comparison, 16 March 1878; cuid2077 (Box 39)
  - Spectra, 20 March 1878; cuid1896 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - CO2, April 1878; cuid1925 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Solar Spectrum with Comparison, 6 April 1878; cuid2075 (Box 39)
  - Solar Spectrum with Comparison Spectrum, 6 April 1878; cuid2050 (Box 37, Folder 13)
  - Solar Spectrum with Comparison Spectrum, 6 April 1878; cuid2051 (Box 37, Folder 14)
  - Solar Spectrum with Comparison Spectrum, 18 April 1878; cuid2065 (Box 39)
  - Laboratory Spectrum, 19 April 1878; cuid2059 (Box 38, Folder 11)
  - Sulphur, 1 June 1878; cuid1885 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Copy of a Corona Taken by A. Clark at Criston, 29 July 1878; cuid2040 (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - Spectra, 1878; cuid1950 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Coal Gas Laboratory Spectrum, 1878; cuid2069 (Box 39)
  - Solar Corona, 1878; cuid2052 (Box 38, Folder 4)
  - Solar Spectrum, 6 January 1879; cuid2045 (Box 37, Folder 8)
  - Spectra -- No. 1, 3 March 1879; cuid1918 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Spectra -- No. 1, 8 March 1879; cuid1917 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Spectra -- No. 2, 8 March 1879; cuid1913 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Spectra -- No. 3, 8 March 1879; cuid1916 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Spectra -- No. 2, 10 March 1879; cuid1915 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Spectra, 9 March 1879; cuid1930 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Spectra, 10 March 1879; cuid1926 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Spectra, 16 March 1879; cuid1921 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Spectra -- No. 2, 26 March 1879; cuid1907 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Spectra -- No. 3, 26 March 1879; cuid1908 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Spectra, 1 April 1879; cuid1929 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Solar Spectrum, 1 April 1879; cuid2046 (Box 37, Folder 9)
  - Solar Spectrum, 2 April 1879; cuid2047 (Box 37, Folder 10)
  - Solar Spectrum, 2 April 1879; cuid2042 (Box 37, Folder 5)
  - Spectra, 4 April 1879; cuid1927 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Spectra -- No. 3, 4 April 1879; cuid1906 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Spectra -- No. 1, 6 April 1879; cuid1914 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Spectra, 6 April 1879; cuid1928 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Bromide of Silicon Laboratory Spectrum, 23 April 1879; cuid2055 (Box 38, Folder 7)
  - Spectra, 11 May 1879; cuid1933 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Solar Spectrum, 15 May 1879; cuid2041 (Box 37, Folder 4)
  - Stellar Spectra Dispersion -- Spectra of Vega and Jupiter, 4 October 1879; cuid1974 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Stellar Spectra Dispersion -- Spectra of Vega and Jupiter, 15 September 1879; cuid14876 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Stellar Spectra Dispersion -- Spectra of Vega and Jupiter, 24 September 1879; cuid14877 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Stellar Spectra Dispersion -- Spetra of Vega and Moon, 26 September 1879; cuid14878 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Stellar Spectra Dispersion -- Spectra of Vega and Moon, 27 September 1879; cuid14879 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Stellar Spectra Dispersion 90A / MM-11 Glass Slide, circa 1879-1881; cuid14881 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Carbon Channeled Spectrum, 23 April 1880; cuid1901 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Carbon Bands Identified, 23 April 1880; cuid1903 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Iron Arc Crucible, 23 April 1880; cuid1904 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Crucible and Sun, 25 April 1880; cuid1886 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Carbon Crucible, 25 April 1880; cuid1887 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Carbon Laboratory Spectrum, 25 April 1880; cuid2058 (Box 38, Folder 10)
  - Carbon and Sun, 1 May 1880; cuid1899 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Carbon In Sun, 1 May 1880; cuid1902 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Granite Spectroscope, 21 May 1880; cuid1895 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Grating -- No. 3, 23 May 1880; cuid1922 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Brating Carbon Crucible, 24 May 1880; cuid1884 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Grating Spectroscope, 24 May 1880; cuid1898 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Grating, 31 May 1880; cuid1894 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Stellar Spectra Dispersion -- Spectra of Arcturus and Moon, 16 June 1880; cuid14880 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Iodine, 17 January 1881; cuid1891 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Photographic Experiment No. 1, 18 January 1881; cuid2015 (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Photographic Experiment No. 2, 18 January 1881; cuid2010 (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Maxim, 21 January 1881; cuid1892 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Photographic Experiment Ex 60th, 22 January 1881; cuid2011 (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Photographic Experiment, 23 January 1881; cuid2014 (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Photographic Experiment, 29 January 1881; cuid2008 (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Photographic Experiment, 6 February 1881; cuid1993 (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Photographic Experiment No. 2, 6 February 1881; cuid1984 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Photographic Experiment Grating, 13 February 1881; cuid2009 (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Photographic Experiment Grating, 13 February 1881; cuid2013 (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Sun Prisms, 20 February 1881; cuid2012 (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Carbon Ore Prisms, 20 February 1881; cuid1994 (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Photographic Experiment No. 1, 22 February 1881; cuid1979 (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Photographic Experiment No. 2, 22 February 1881; cuid1987 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - No. 1 90S, 24 February 1881; cuid1996 (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - No. 2 5M Slit 14 / 5000, 24 February 1881; cuid1977 (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Carbon Ore 90S, 25 February 1881; cuid1985 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Carbon Ore, 1 March 1881; cuid1986 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - 8648 Carbon Ore, 1 March 1881; cuid1976 (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - 90S Carbon Ore, 1 March 1881; cuid1978 (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Painted on Black, 11 March 1881; cuid1980 (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - (?) That I Have and in Stellar (?) Up to Present, 11 March 1881; cuid2025 (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - Eastman, 11 March 1881; cuid1975 (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - New Eastman No. 1 Experiment, 5 April 1881; cuid2004 (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - New Eastman No. 2 Experiment, 5 April 1881; cuid2001 (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Old Lantern No. 2 Experiment, 5 April 1881; cuid2002 (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - New Eastman No. 1 Experiment, 6 April 1881; cuid1998 (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - New Eastman No. 2 Experiment, 6 April 1881; cuid2005 (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Old Eastman No. 1 Experiment, 6 April 1881; cuid2000 (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Old Eastman No. 2 Experiment, 6 April 1881; cuid1999 (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - New Eastman Oxalate, 7 April 1881; cuid1997 (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Old Lantern Pyrogallic Experiments, 7 April 1881; cuid1981 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Old Lantern Oxalate Experiment, 7 April 1881; cuid1982 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Old Lantern Oxalate Experiment, 7 April 1881; cuid1983 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Photographic Experiment, 7 April 1881; cuid1988 (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Exposed Oxidate, 7 April 1881; cuid1989 (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Photographic Experiment, 11 April 1881; cuid2022 (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Photographic Experiment, 17 April 1881; cuid1992 (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Photographic Experiment, 19 April 1881; cuid1990 (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Photographic Experiment, 23 April 1881; cuid1991 (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Stellar Spectra Dispersion -- Spectra of Vega and Moon, 8 August 1881; cuid14882 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Stellar Spectra Dispersion -- Spectra of Vega and Moon, 12 August, circa 1881; cuid14883 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Stellar Spectra Dispersion -- Spectra of Vega and Moon, 16 August 1881; cuid14884 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Stellar Spectra Dispersion -- Spectra of Arcturus and Vega, 23 August 1881; cuid14885 (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Focus Photography, 11 March 1882; cuid2018 (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Photographic Experiment No. 1, 28 May 1882; cuid2020 (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Photographic Experiment No. 2, 28 May 1882; cuid2021 (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Sun 105 Oxygen, 11 June 1882; cuid2019 (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Sun 10S, 11 June 1882; cuid1995 (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Carbon, 10 July 1882; cuid2017 (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Spectra, January, undated; cuid1897 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Spectra, 14 January, undated; cuid1959 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Brass, 25 February, undated; cuid1972 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Spectra, 31 May, undated; cuid1890 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Spectra, 12 June, undated; cuid1889 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Spectra, undated; cuid1909 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Spectra, undated; cuid1910 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Spectra, undated; cuid1920 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Spectra, undated; cuid1963 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Spectra, undated; cuid1931 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Spectra, undated; cuid1934 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Spectra, undated; cuid1951 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Spectra, undated; cuid1943 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Spectra, undated; cuid1944 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Spectra, undated; cuid1945 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Spectra, undated; cuid1946 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Spectra, undated; cuid1947 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Puppis -- Spectrum 3923-4505, undated; cuid2016 (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Hydrogen -- No Leyden, undated; cuid1965 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Photographic Experiment, undated; cuid2023 (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - Sun and Air, undated; cuid2024 (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - Solar Spectrum, undated; cuid2048 (Box 37, Folder 11)
  - Enlarged Copy of Solar Spectrum, undated; cuid2043 (Box 37, Folder 6)
  - Solar Spectrum with Comparison, undated; cuid2068 (Box 39)
  - Solar Comparison Spectrum, undated; cuid2049 (Box 37, Folder 12)
  - Solar Spectrum with Comparison Spectrum, undated; cuid2053 (Box 38, Folder 5)
  - Coal Gas Laboratory Spectrum, undated; cuid2056 (Box 38, Folder 8)
  - Canis Minoris, undated; cuid1935 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Leyden, undated; cuid1969 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Sun, undated; cuid1942 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Photographic Experiment, undated; cuid2003 (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Solar? Spectrum, undated; cuid2028 (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - Solar? Spectrum, undated; cuid2031 (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - Objective Prism Plate, undated; cuid2029 (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - Objective Prism Plate, undated; cuid2032 (Box 34, Folder 7)
  - Objective Prism Plate -- Probably Pleiades, undated; cuid2033 (Box 34, Folder 8)
  - Objective Prism Plate, undated; cuid2034 (Box 34, Folder 9)
  - Objective Prism Plate -- Star Field, undated; cuid2035 (Box 34, Folder 10)
  - Objective Prism Plate, undated; cuid2036 (Box 34, Folder 11)
  - Objective Prism Plate, undated; cuid2037 (Box 34, Folder 12)
  - Objective Prism Plate -- Arcturus, undated; cuid2038 (Box 34, Folder 13)
  - Copy of Stellar Emission Spectrum No. 23 -- Probably a Reproduction of Draper's Own Plate, undated; cuid2026 (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Spectrum No. 24, undated; cuid2030 (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - No. 20; D186; 13, undated; cuid1941 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - No. 21; D187; 13, undated; cuid1936 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - No. 22; D204; G; 26, undated; cuid1937 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - 17; 0201; 12, undated; cuid1938 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - 18; D198; 12, undated; cuid1939 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Series II. Henry Draper Moon Images, 1862, 1872, undated; 2 Linear Feet in 2 custom boxes and 1 oversize flat box.
  This series contains images of the moon dating from 1862 to circa 1882 taken by New York University professor, dean of medicine, and amateur astrophotographer Henry Draper.
  - Moon, 16 August 1862; cuid14891 (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - Moon, 17 August 1862; cuid14890 (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - Moon, 17 August 1862; cuid14892 (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - 30 Second Exposure, 24 July 1872; cuid14871 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - 10-40 Second Exposure, 5 August 1872; cuid14872 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - 10 Second Exposure, 18 August 1872; cuid14873 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Last Quarter Moon, 24 August 1872; cuid14550 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Moon Image Taken with 28" Telescope, 1872; cuid14551 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Moon Image Taken with 28" Telescope, 1872; cuid14552 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Moon Image Taken with 28" Telescope, 1872; cuid14553 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Moon Image Taken with 28" Telescope, 1872; cuid14554 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Moon Image Taken with 28" Telescope, 1872; cuid14555 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Moon Image Taken with 28" Telescope, 1872; cuid14556 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Moon Image Taken with 28" Telescope, 1872; cuid14557 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Moon, circa late 19th century; cuid14558 (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - Moon, circa late 19th century; cuid14889 (Box 30, Folder 10)
- Series III. Glass Plate Negative Fragments, 1872-1879, undated; 2.50 Linear Feet in 1 card box, 3 oversize flat boxes, and 6 custom boxes.
  This series contains broken fragments of glass plate negatives and lantern slides which, due to their subject matter, are assumed to be Henry Draper astrophotographic images. Many are undated. Image subjects include spectra, solar spectrum, and segments of a solar disk.
  - Spectrum, December 1872; cuid14850 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Spectra, 3 April 1877; cuid14832 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Spectra, 3 April 1877; cuid14831 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Solar Spectrum?, 26 March 1879; cuid14864 (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Spectra, undated; cuid14834 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Spectra, undated; cuid14811 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Spectra, undated; cuid14812 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Spectra, undated; cuid14813 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Spectra, undated; cuid14814 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Spectra -- Auriagae, undated; cuid14815 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Spectra, undated; cuid14816 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Spectra, undated; cuid14818 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Spectra, undated; cuid14819 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Spectra, undated; cuid14820 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Fragment, undated; cuid14821 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Spectra, undated; cuid14822 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Spectra, undated; cuid14823 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Spectra, undated; cuid14824 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Spectra, undated; cuid14825 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Fragment, undated; cuid14826 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Spectra, undated; cuid14827 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Spectra, undated; cuid14828 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Spectra, undated; cuid14829 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Spectra, undated; cuid14830 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Spectra, undated; cuid14836 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Spectra, undated; cuid14837 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Spectra, undated; cuid14838 (Box 22, Folder 2)